Now just some simple rules to follow.
First of all, when you're at work don't send personal emails.
That's just bad news all the way around.
If you have to send a personal email I would certainly make sure that the boss knew that you were going to send a personal email.
I'm pretty sure that people have been fired for doing way too much personal business via the Internet or emails when they're at work.
All you want to talk about in your emails at work is work.
You want to plan your message carefully.
You want to talk about goals, you want to talk about schedules, you want to talk about research, you want to talk about meetings, you want to talk about company news.
Keep everything personal out of it.
When I talk about personal messages, you don't want to send personal messages to your friends but you don't want personal information in your business emails like you're sending an email to a co-worker but you're busy talking in your email about what a jerk the boss is.
That's a bad idea because anyone at any time can have access to these emails.
Personal information in writing via email will always come back to haunt you.
Don't do it.